It was a dangerous time to be a woman. And a good time to have friends.
Bad Girls is a romance, western film directed by Jonathan Kaplan.
Four former harlots try to leave the wild west (Colorado, to be exact)
and head north to make a better life for themselves.
Unfortunately someone from Cody's past won't let it happen that easily.
Cody Zamora, played by Madeleine Stowe.
Anita Crown, played by Mary Stuart Masterson.
Eileen Spenser, played by Andie MacDowell.
Lily Laronette, played by Drew Barrymore.
Kid Jarrett, played by James Russo.
William Tucker, played by James LeGros.
Bad Girls is a 1994 American Western film directed by Jonathan
Kaplan, and written by Ken Friedman and Yolande Turner.
It stars Madeleine Stowe, Mary Stuart Masterson,
Andie MacDowell, and Drew Barrymore.
The film follows four former prostitutes on the run following a justifiable homicide and prison
escape, who later encounter difficulties involving bank robbery and Pinkerton detectives.
The film was originally conceived as a feminist Western and a low-budget independent film,
until producers Albert Ruddy and André Morgan brought in 20th Century Fox.
The involvement of a major studio substantially increased the film's
budget and necessitated the casting of big-name actresses.
Principal photography began in July 1993 in Sonora, California with director Tamra Davis at the helm, but shortly
into filming, producers fired Davis and reconceptualized the movie to be more of an action film.
Jonathan Kaplan was hired to replace Davis.
Bad Girls opened in North American theaters on April 22, 1994.
It received largely negative reviews and was a box office disappointment, with critics opining
that the film squandered its encouraging premise and misused its four female leads.
The film explores themes of blonde, revenge, tough girl, wild west, fast draw.
The tone is emotional.